A Guide to the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad Records, 1834-1997
Library of Virginia
- Series XXIV: Richmond-Washington Co., 1901-1971, .47 cubic feet and 1 volume. (Box 313-314)
  Incorporated in 1901 in New Jersey; includes some data on Wash. South R.Y. Co. This series includes subseries A: Legal Department and B: Finance Department. The legal volume contains by-laws and certificate of incorporation, 5 Sept. 1901; the six party agreement that led to the company's founding, 31 July 1901; and a Collateral Trust Mortgage and Agreement, 1 June 1903. Financial files, 1901-1971 consist of annual reports, a stock analysis for 1950-1959, an evaluation of the company's condition, 1914; as well as an organizational chart outlining ownerships and financial interests of the Richmond-Washington Company and its subsidiaries.
  - XXIV.A. Legal Department, 1901-1903
    - Bylaws and Certificate of Incorporation, 5 Sep 1901; Agreements, 31 Jul 1901; and Collateral Trust Mortgage and Agreement, 1 Jun 1903, 1 vol. (Box 313)
  - XXIV.B. Finance Department, 1901-1971
    Some Tax information is included in R.F. & P. Federal Income Tax files
    - XXIV.B.1. Annual Report Files, 1901-1971
      Includes for the most part correspondence, expenditures, expenses, betterments, and Annual Reports.
      - Fiscal year 1906-1907, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 313:1)
        No report for 1909.
      - Fiscal year 1911-1912 (Box-folder 313:2)
        No report for 1911.
      - Fiscal year 1913-1915 (Box-folder 313:3)
      - Fiscal year 1916-1917 (Box-folder 313:4)
      - Fiscal year 1918-1920 (Box-folder 313:5)
      - Fiscal year 1921-1923 (Box-folder 313:6)
      - Fiscal year 1924-1929 (Box-folder 313:7)
      - Fiscal year 1930-1933 (Box-folder 313:8)
      - Fiscal year 1934-1937 (Box-folder 313:9)
      - Fiscal year 1938-1944 (Box-folder 313:10)
      - Fiscal year 1945, 1947-1949, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 313:11)
      - Fiscal year 1958-1963 (Box-folder 314:1)
      - Fiscal year, 1967-1968, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 314:2)
        No reports for 1968 and 1970.
    - XXIV.B.2. Miscellaneous Files
      - Corporate Structure as of 31 Dec 1939, Reconstruction Finance Corp., Railroad Division, 1 sheet (Oversize 344:35)
      - Physical and Financial Conditions of Richmond-Washington Co., With View and Recommendations of Chesapeake and Ohio R.Y. Co. and Southern R.Y. Co., In respect to providing Revenues Adequate to Meet its Obligations 3 Jul 1914 (Box-folder 314:3)
        Includes agreement 31 Jul 1901, that led to Co.'s incorporation
      - Stock Analysis, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 314:4)
- Series XXV: Seaboard Air Line Railroad Co., 1947
  - Application No. 4 of Seaboard Air Line Railroad Company under Section 20 a of the Interstate Commerce Act, 19 November 1947, 1 volume. (Box 314)
- Series XXVI: South Washington Land Corporation, 1957-1975, .45 cubic feet and 1 volume. (Box 314-315)
  Incorporated August 1957 and merged into Richmond Land Corporation in 1975. This series is divided into Subseries A: General Administration and Management; Subseries B: Legal Department; and Subseries C: Finance Department. Included are minutes, 1957-1975; articles of incorporation and bylaws, 1957, 1968; as well as financial files, 1965-1968, consisting of check stubs and real estate tax information for 1971-1972.
  - XXVI.A. General Administration, Management, 1957-1975
    - Minute Book, Aug 1957-Jul 1975, 1 vol. (Box 314)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, 17 Apr 1961 (Box-folder 314:5)
    - Stockholders Annual Meeting, 17 Apr 1961 (Box-folder 314:5)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, 16 Apr 1962 (Box-folder 314:6)
    - Stockholders Annual Meeting, 16 Apr 1962 (Box-folder 314:6)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, 15 Apr 1963 (Box-folder 314:7)
    - Stockholders Annual Meeting, 15 Apr 1963 (Box-folder 314:7)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, 20 Apr 1964 (Box-folder 314:8)
    - Stockholders Annual Meeting, 20 Apr 1964 (Box-folder 314:8)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, 19 Apr 1965 (Box-folder 314:9)
    - Stockholders Annual Meeting, 19 Apr 1965 (Box-folder 314:9)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, 18 Apr 1966 (Box-folder 314:10)
    - Stockholders Annual Meeting, 18 Apr 1966 (Box-folder 314:10)
    - Board of Directors Meetings, 17 Apr, 10 May, 13 Jun 1967 (Box-folder 314:11)
    - Stockholders Annual Meeting, 17 Apr 1967 (Box-folder 314:11)
    - Board of Directors Meetings, 30 Jan, 15 Apr 1968 (Box-folder 315:1)
    - Stockholders Annual Meeting, 15 Apr 1968 (Box-folder 315:1)
    - Board of Directors Meetings, 21 Apr, 26 Aug, 13 Oct, 10 Nov 1969 (Box-folder 315:2)
    - Stockholders Annual Meeting, 21 Apr 1968 (Box-folder 315:2)
    - Board of Directors Meetings, 16 Jan, 16 Apr, 8 Jul, 30 Oct 1970, 14 Jul 1971 (Box-folder 315:3)
    - Stockholders Annual Meeting, 20 Apr 1970 (Box-folder 315:4)
  - XXVI.B. Legal Department, 1957, 1968
    - Articles of Incorporation and Bylaws, 1957,1968 (Box-folder 315:5)
      Includes minutes of Organization Meeting, 4 Sep 1957
  - XXVI.C. Finance Department, 1965-1975
    - Check Stubs No. 101-352, 8 Feb 1965-14 May 1970 (Box-folder 315:6)
    - Check stubs No. 353-602, 9 Jun 1970-1 Mar 1974 (Box-folder 315:7)
    - Check stubs No. 603-713, 1 Mar 1974-11 Sep 1975 (Box-folder 315:8)
    - Real Estate Taxes, 1971-1972, 1975 (Box-folder 315:9)
- Series XXVII: Suburban Motor Corporation, 1928-1929, 1 volume. (Box 316)
  This series includes one Minute book for Board of Directors and Stockholders Meetings, 1928-1929 with Articles of Association and Bylaws; it covers the time from the company's incorporation on 5 July 1928 to its merger into the R.F.& P. Transportation Co. in 1929.
  - XXVII.A. General Administration, Management, 1928-1929
    - Minute Book, Board of Directors and Stockholders 5 Jul 1928-15 Apr 1929, 1 vol. (Box 316)
      Includes: Articles of Association and Bylaws
      Do not serve original. Available on microfilm, Misc. Reel 2174
- Series XXVIII: Trailer Train Co., 1959-1966, 2 file folders. (Box 316)
  Included are annual reports from 1959 to 1966.
  - Annual Reports, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 316:10)
  - Annual Reports, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 316:11)
- Series XXIX: Virginia and Carolina Railroad Co., 1882-1886, 2 volumes. (Box 317)
  Includes two stock certificate books, dating from 1882-1886, that document purchase of stocks by R.F.& P. president Joseph P. Brinton, and Moncure Robinson, who was the company's president from 1840-1847.
  - Stock certificate book, 11 Jan 1882-5 Jun 1883, 1 vol. (Box 317)
  - Stock certificate book, 3 Jul 1883-20 May 1886, 1 vol. (Box 317)
- Series XXX: Washington and Fredericksburg Steamboat Co., 1840-1871, 2 volumes and one oversize folder. (Box 318, 344)
  Includes securities for this predecessor of the Potomac Steamboat Co. (see above): Dividend warrants in the value of $100 and $500, issued in 1848, a stock certificate book, 1840-1855, and a stock transfer register, 1845-1871.
  - Dividend Warrants, $100 and $500, issued 1848 (Oversize 344:36)
  - Stock certificate book, 25 Apr 1840-23 Oct 1855, 1 vol. and inserts (Box 318)
  - Stock transfer register, 17 Oct 1845-25 May 1871, 1 vol. and inserts (Box 318)
- Series XXXI: Washington Southern Railway Co., 1871-1925, 4.5 cubic feet and 40 volumes. (Box 319-343)
  Incorporated in 1890 through the consolidation of A & F R.Y. and A & W R.Y.. This series consists of minutes, legal files, financial files, and miscellaneous files. The two volumes of Board of Directors and Stockholders Meeting Minutes, 1890-1920 cover the company's thirty years of existence, the Minutes of the Potomac Yard Advisory Board, 1909-1925 continue for 5 years after the Washington Southern R.Y. Co. was merged completely into the R.F.& P., which took over its place on the Board. The Advisory Board was made up of all five railroad companies using Potomac Yard. In addition to the Washington Southern R.Y. Co., those were the Baltimore & Ohio R.R. Co., the Chesapeake & Ohio R.Y. Co., the Philadelphia, Baltimore & Washington R.R. Co. and the Southern R.Y. Co. Legal records, 1871-1917 include copies of charter, bylaws and mortgages, an indexed volume of contracts and agreements, as well as about 150 deeds. Also included are pre-1890 deeds that were made by one of the company's predecessors, the Alexandria & Fredericksburg R.Y. Co. (see above). Financial files, 1890-1921 include Treasurer's correspondence, accounting and bookkeeping records, and securities. The correspondence is made up of one letter book, 1890-1904; the accounting and bookkeeping records contain annual reports, balances, betterments, check registers, journals, and ledgers. The securities subseries includes stock and bonds ledgers, transfers and certificates as well as 4% and 5% gold and mortgage bonds. The miscellaneous file contains a brief corporate history until 1907. R.F. & P. tax records also include data for Washington Southern R.Y.
  - XXXI.A. General Administration, Management: Minutes, 1890-1925
    - XXXI.A.1. Board of Directors and Stockholders, 1890-1920
      - Minute Book No. 1, Board of Directors and Stockholders, 26 Mar 1890-15 Sep 1910 (indexed) (Box 319)
        Do not serve original. Available on microfilm, Misc. Reel 2176
      - Minute Book, Board of Directors and Stockholders, 20 Oct 1910-26 May 1920 (indexed) (Box 320)
    - XXXI.A.2. Potomac Yard, Advisory Board, 18 May 1909-25 Sep 1925
      - Wash. South. R.Y. Co. and R.F. & P. R.Y. Co., Advisory Board of Potomac Yard, Minute Book (Box 321)
        Do not serve original. Available on microfilm, Misc. Reel 2177
  - XXXI.B. Legal Department 1871-1917
    - XXXI.B.1. Charters and Bylaws, 1890-1910
      - Charters, Bylaws, Mortgages, etc., 1890-1903, 1 vol.; 3 copies (varying in some annotations and inserts) (Box 322)
        Compilation includes the Agreement of the Consolidation of A. & F. R.Y. Co., and the Charter granted 1903; Bylaws, 1901; First (Gold) Mortgage, 1903; Collateral Trust Mortgage, 1903; as well as an agreement, 1903.
      - Bylaws(...) Approved and Adopted 21 Nov 1910 (Box-folder 322:1)
    - XXXI.B.2. Contracts, Agreements, and Deeds, 1871-1917
      - Contracts and Agreements, 6 Nov 1910-3 Oct 1903 (indexed), 1 vol. (Box 323)
      - No. 1006, Deed (First Track) 1 May 1901 (Box-folder 324:1)
      - No. 1007, Deed (First Track) 9 Mar 1904 (Box-folder 324:1)
      - No. 1008, A. & F. R.Y. Co.; Act granting right of Way (First Track) 25 Apr 1871 (Box-folder 324:1)
      - No. 1010, A. & F. R.Y. Co., Deed (First Track) 14 Dec 1871 (Box-folder 324:1)
      - No. 1012, Deed (First Track) 5 Aug 1898 (Box-folder 324:2)
      - No. 1013, A. & F. R.Y. Co./Potomac Land and Improvement Co., Deed (First Track) 4 Jun 1872 (Box-folder 324:3)
      - No. 1014, A. & F. R.Y. Co., Deed (First Track) MISSING (envelope and letter with offer to use land pertaining to G.B. Newton free of charge 2 Dec 1870 (Box-folder 324:3)
      - No. 1015, A. & F. R.Y. Co., Deed (First Track); includes Abstract of Title 3 Sep 1868 [15 Nov 1890] (Box-folder 324:4)
      - No. 1018, A. & F. R.Y. Co., Deed (First Track) 28 Jun 1890 (Box-folder 324:5)
      - No. 1019, A. & F. R.Y. Co., Deed (First Track); includes Abstract of Title 26 Nov 1889 (Box-folder 324:6)
      - No. 1020, A. & F. R.Y. Co., Deed (First Track) 2 Nov 1918 (Box-folder 324:6)
      - No. 1021, Deed (First Track); includes Abstract of Title 21 Sep 1888 [21 Oct 1893] (Box-folder 324:7)
      - No. 1023, Deed (First Track); includes Abstract of Title 11 Dec 1889 (Box-folder 324:8)
      - No. 1025, A. & F. R.Y. Co., Deed (First Track); includes Abstract of Title 9 Mar 1882 [20 Nov 1889] (Box-folder 324:9)
      - No. 1026, Deed (First Track) 8 Nov 1890 (Box-folder 325:1)
      - No. 1027, Deed (First Track) 8 Nov 1890 (Box-folder 325:1)
      - No. 1028, Deed (First Track) 27 Mar 1886 (Box-folder 325:1)
      - No. 1029, Correspondence with Richmond & Danville R.R. Co. (Box-folder 325:2)
      - No. 1030, Court Order: Division of the Alexander Estate (First Track) 21 Jun 1769, copy (Box-folder 325:3)
      - No. 1031, Computation (First Track) ca. 1889 (Box-folder 325:3)
      - No. 1032, Agreement of Consolidation of the A. & R. R.Y. Co. and the A. & W. R.Y. Co [...] forming one company under the name of the Washington Southern Railway Co. 3 Mar 1890 (Box-folder 325:3)
      - No. 1033, Rent of Leasehold 1 Oct 1890 (Box-folder 325:3)
      - No. 1034, Deed (First Track) Feb 1893 (Box-folder 325:4)
      - No. 1035, Notation on title (First Track) 29 Jun 1891 (Box-folder 325:4)
      - No. 1036, Brief and Opinion (First Track) n.d. (Box-folder 325:4)
      - No. 1037, Deed (First Track) MISSING (cover letter 29 Jun 1891 only) (Box-folder 325:4)
      - No. 1038, Brief of Title and Opinion on Holmes' or Alexanders' Island (First Track) (Box-folder 325:5)
      - No. 1039, Chief Conveyer Statement (First Track) MISSING (correspondence only) 26 Jun 1888 (Box-folder 325:6)
      - No. 1040, Correspondence re: Property at South End Long Bridge (First Track) 1901 (Box-folder 325:7)
      - No. 1041, Deed (First Track) 1 May 1901 (Box-folder 325:7)
      - No. 1042, Deed (First Track) 9 Mar 1904 (Box-folder 325:7)
      - No. 1043, Deed (First Track) 23 Jun 1904 (Box-folder 326:1)
      - No. 1044, Deed (First Track) 27 Jul 1903 (Box-folder 326:1)
      - No. 1045, First Mortgage; Deed of Release 28 Jun 1890; 30 Sep 1901 (Box-folder 326:2)
      - No. 1047, Deed (First Track) 5 Nov 1887 (Box-folder 326:3)
      - No. 1048, A. & F. R.Y. Co., Deed (First Track); includes Abstract of Title 27 Oct 1862, 16 Jul 1867, 15 Nov 1889 (Box-folder 326:4)
      - No. 1049, A. & W. R.R. Co., Deed (First Track) 18 Apr 1855 (Box-folder 326:4)
      - No. 1050, Correspondence only (First Track) 1896-1924 (Box-folder 326:5)
      - No. 1053, Deed (Second Track) 16 Dec 1903 (Box-folder 326:6)
      - No. 1054, Deed (Second Track) 2 Jul 1904 (Box-folder 326:6)
      - No. 1056, Deed 13 Nov 1903 (Box-folder 326:6)
      - No. 1057, Deed (Second Track) 27 Jun 1903 (Box-folder 327:1)
      - No. 1058, Deed (Second Track) 24 Jun 1904 (Box-folder 327:1)
      - No. 1060, Deed (Second Track) 28 Jun 1904 (Box-folder 327:1)
      - No. 1061, Deed (Second Track) 9 Jun 1903 (Box-folder 327:2)
      - No. 1063, Deed (Second Track) 18 Nov 1905 (Box-folder 327:2)
      - No. 1064, Deed (Second Track) 2 Oct 1905 (Box-folder 327:2)
      - No. 1067, Deed (Second Track) 27 Jun 1904 (Box-folder 327:2)
      - No. 1068, Deed (Second Track) 5 Sep 1904 (Box-folder 327:3)
      - No. 1069, Deed (Second Track) 14 Dec 1903 (Box-folder 327:3)
      - No. 1070, Deed (Second Track) 2 Oct 1905 (Box-folder 327:3)
      - No. 1071, Deed (Second Track) 17 Mar 1904 (Box-folder 327:4)
      - No. 1072, Deed (Second Track) 19 May 1903 (Box-folder 327:4)
      - No. 1073, Deed 6 Jul 1903 (Box-folder 327:4)
      - No. 1074, Deed 26 Jul 1903 (Box-folder 327:5)
      - No. 1075, Deed (Second Track) 8 Jun 1903 (Box-folder 327:5)
      - No. 1076, Deed (Second Track) 11 Jul 1903 (Box-folder 327:6)
      - No. 1077, Deed (Second Track) 18 Jan 1904, MISSING (Box-folder 327:6)
      - No. 1080, Deed (Second Track) 2 Jul 1904 (Box-folder 327:6)
      - No. 1081, Deed (Second Track) 24 Jun 1904 (Box-folder 327:6)
      - No. 1083, Deed (Second Track) 26 Jan 1904 (Box-folder 327:7)
      - No. 1084, Deed 25 Jul 1903, 6 May 1904 (Box-folder 327:7)
      - No. 1085, Deed 25 Jul 1903 (Box-folder 327:7)
      - No. 1086, Deed (Second Track) 19 May 1903 (Box-folder 327:8)
      - No. 1087, Deed (Second Track) 15 Nov 1906 (Box-folder 327:8)
      - No. 1088, Deed (Second Track) 26 Apr 1904 (Box-folder 327:8)
      - No. 1097, Deed (Second Track) 1 Jul 1904 (Box-folder 327:9)
      - No. 1099, Deed (Second Track) 7 Nov 1905 (Box-folder 327:9)
      - No. 1101, Deed (Second Track) 17 Sep 1902 (Box-folder 327:9)
      - No. 1102, Deed (Second Track) 4 Aug, 5 Sep 1904, 17 May 1915 (Box-folder 328:1)
      - No. 1103, Deed (Second Track) 5 Sep 1904 (Box-folder 328:1)
      - No. 1104, Deed (Second Track) 7 Jul 1904 (Box-folder 328:1)
      - No. 1105, Deed (Second Track) 18 Jun 1903 (Box-folder 328:2)
      - No. 1106, Deed (Second Track) 7 Aug 1903, 16 Feb 1907 (Box-folder 328:2)
      - No. 1107, Deed (Second Track) 16 Nov 1904 (Box-folder 328:2)
      - No. 1108, Deed (Second Track) 18 Jun 1903 (Box-folder 328:3)
      - No. 1109, Deed (Second Track) 22 Apr 1904 (Box-folder 328:3)
      - No. 1110, Deed (Second Track) 13 Aug 1903 (Box-folder 328:3)
      - No. 1111, Deed (Second Track) 12 Aug 1903, 14 Oct 1903 (Box-folder 328:4)
      - No. 1112, Deed (Second Track) 3 Dec 1903 (Box-folder 328:4)
      - No. 1113, Deed (Second Track) 20 Oct 1902 (Box-folder 328:4)
      - No. 1115, Release (Second Track) 13 Jul 1905 (Box-folder 328:5)
      - No. 1116, Deed (Second Track) 7 Jul 1904 (Box-folder 328:5)
      - No. 1118, Deed (Second Track) 27 Jun 1904 (Box-folder 328:5)
      - No. 1124, Deed (Second Track) 5 Sep 1904 (Box-folder 328:6)
      - No. 1126, Deed (Second Track) 25 Jul 1903 (Box-folder 328:6)
      - No. 1127, Deed (Second Track) 5 Sep 1905, 14 May 1906 (Box-folder 328:7)
      - No. 1128, Deed (Second Track) 14 Mar 1904 (Box-folder 328:8)
      - No. 1131, Deed (Second Track) 24 Jun 1904 (Box-folder 328:8)
      - No. 1132, Deed (Second Track) 3 Aug 1903 (Box-folder 328:8)
      - No. 1133, Deed (Second Track) 30 Jun 1904 (Box-folder 328:9)
      - No. 1134, Deed (Second Track) 19 Jun 1903 (Box-folder 328:9)
      - No. 1135, Deed (Second Track) 10 Nov 1903 (Box-folder 328:9)
      - No. 1136, Deed (Second Track) 27 Jun 1904 (Box-folder 328:9)
      - No. 1137, Deed (Second Track) 27 Jun 1904 (Box-folder 329:1)
      - No. 1138, Deed (Second Track) 4 Jun 1903, 23 Feb 1905 (Box-folder 329:1)
      - No. 1140, A. & F. R.Y. Co., Deed (Second Track) 11 May 1875 (Box-folder 329:1)
      - No. 1141, Deed (Second Track) 24 Dec 1903, 20, 29 Jul 1904 (Box-folder 329:2)
      - No. 1142, Deed (Second Track) 17, 12 Nov 1903, 13 Dec 1904 (Box-folder 329:3)
      - No. 1143, Deed (Second Track) 18 Jun 1903, 29 Jul 1904 (Box-folder 329:3)
      - No. 1144, Deed (Second Track) 22 Oct 1903 (Box-folder 329:4)
      - No. 1145, Deed (Second Track) 25 May 1903 (Box-folder 329:4)
      - No. 1146, Deed (Second Track) 26 Apr 1904 (Box-folder 329:4)
      - No. 1147, Deed (Second Track) 19 Aug 1904 (Box-folder 329:5)
      - No. 1150, Deed (Second Track) 24 Apr 1904 (Box-folder 329:5)
      - No. 1153, Deed (Second Track) 14 Oct 1904 (Box-folder 329:6)
      - No. 1155, Deed (Second Track) 45 Sep 1904 (Box-folder 329:6)
      - No. 1160, Deed (Second Track) 29 May 1903 (Box-folder 329:7)
      - No. 1162, Deed (Second Track) 1 Jul 1904 (Box-folder 329:7)
      - No. 1164, Deed (Second Track) 13 Aug 1903 (Box-folder 329:7)
      - No. 1165, Deed (Second Track) 17 Jun 1903, 7 Apr 1904 (Box-folder 330:1)
      - No. 1166, Deed (Second Track) 8 Jun 1903 (Box-folder 330:2)
      - No. 1167, Deed (Second Track) 8 Jun 1903 (Box-folder 330:3)
      - No. 1168, Deed (Second Track) 8 Jun 1903 (Box-folder 330:3)
      - No. 1169, Deed (Second Track) 25 May 1903 (Box-folder 330:3)
      - No. 1170, Deed (Second Track) 6 Jun 1903 (Box-folder 330:4)
      - No. 1171, Deed 3 Aug, 7 Sep 1903, 6 May 1904 (Box-folder 330:4)
      - No. 1173, Deed 22 May 1909 (Box-folder 330:5)
      - No. 1175, Deed (Second Track) 21 Jul 1916 (Box-folder 330:5)
      - No. 1178, Deed (Second Track) 18 Jan 1910 (Box-folder 330:6)
      - No. 1179, (envelope only) (Box-folder 330:7)
      - No. 1182, Deed 6 Dec 1910, 9 Mar 1911 (Box-folder 330:7)
      - No. 1183, Lease 15 Feb 1912 (Box-folder 330:8)
      - No. 1184, Deed 11 Aug 1913 (Box-folder 330:9)
      - No. 1187, Deed; MISSING (envelope only) 25 Apr 1914 (Box-folder 331:1)
      - No. 1190, Potomac Railroad/Rotomac and Manassas Railroad, Deed (Second Track) 1 Jan 1872 (Box-folder 331:1)
      - No. 1203, Condemnation 30 Apr 1903 (Box-folder 331:2)
      - No. 1204, Court case 13 May 1904 (Box-folder 331:2)
      - No. 1215, Deed; MISSING (envelope only) 8 Sep 1888 (Box-folder 331:2)
      - No. 1235, Condemnation 17 Sep 1903 (Box-folder 331:3)
      - No. 1236, Condemnation 17 Sep 1903 (Box-folder 331:4)
      - No. 1237, Condemnation 27 Jan 1904 (Box-folder 331:5)
      - No. 1239, Deed 11 May 1868 (Box-folder 331:5)
      - No. 1241, Deed 27 Jul 1917 (Box-folder 331:6)
      - No. 1242, Deed 5 Jul, 24 Aug 1917 (Box-folder 331:7-8)
      - No. 1243, Deed (Conveying to the Southern Railway Co. what was formerly known as the Henry St. Track) 20 May 1909 (Box-folder 331:9)
      - No. 1244, Deed 31 Oct 1901 (Box-folder 331:9)
      - No. 1245, Deed (taking over Occoquan Bridge) 29 Aug 1916 (Box-folder 331:10)
      - No. 1246, Condemnation proceedings 29 Dec 1908, 27 Oct 1909 (Box-folder 332:1)
      - No. 1247, Deed (Crossing over Braddock County Rd.) 7 Apr 1904 (Box-folder 332:1)
      - No. 1248, Deed (Dodge & Wentworth property) 8 Nov 1890 (Box-folder 332:2)
      - No. 1249, Deed (parcel of Land in Fairfax County), Southern Railway Co. and Washington Southern Railway Co. 24 Jun 1905 (Box-folder 332:2)
  - XXXI.C. Finance Department, 1890-1921
    Includes: 1. Treasurer's Correspondence; 2. Accounting and Bookkeeping; 3. Securities
    - XXXI.C.1. Treasurer's Correspondence, 1890-1904
      - Office of the Treasurer, Letters A, 19 Apr 1890-20 Jun 1904, 1 vol. (Box 332)
        Comment on last page: "all letters after this date to be copied in R.F. & P. Letter book"
    - XXXI.C.2. Accounting and Bookkeeping, 1891-1921
      - Annual Reports, 1901-1907 inclusive, 1 vol.; 2 copies (Box 332)
        President's copy and Asst. to President's copy
      - Annual Reports, 1901-1918, By-Laws Adopted Nov. 21, 1910, Agreement of Merger, 1 vol. (Box 333)
        Treasurer's copy
      - Annual Meeting of the Stockholders, 1904, 2 copies (Box-folder 333:1)
      - Annual Meeting of the Stockholders, 1905 (Box-folder 333:1)
      - Annual Meeting of the Stockholders, 1906, 2 copies (Box-folder 333:1)
      - Annual Meeting of the Stockholders, 1907 (Box-folder 333:2)
      - Annual Meeting of the Stockholders, 1908, 2 copies (Box-folder 333:2)
      - Annual Meeting of the Stockholders, 1909, 2 copies (Box-folder 333:2)
      - Annual Meeting of the Stockholders, 1910, 2 copies (Box-folder 333:2)
      - Annual Reports, 1908-1915 inclusive, with By-laws Adopted Nov. 21, 1910 (General Council's copy), 1 vol. (Box 333)
      - Annual Reports, 1908-1915 inclusive, with By-laws Adopted Nov. 21, 1910 (Secretary's copy), 1 vol. (Box 334)
      - Annual Reports, 1911, 2 copies (Box-folder 334:1)
      - Annual Reports, 1912, 2 copies (Box-folder 334:1)
      - Annual Reports, 1913 (Box-folder 334:1)
      - Annual Reports, 1914 (Box-folder 334:2)
      - Annual Reports, 1915, 2 copies (Box-folder 334:2)
      - Annual Reports, Fiscal Year ending 30 Jun 1916, 2 copies (Box-folder 334:2)
      - Annual Reports, Fiscal Year Jul-Dec 1916, 2 copies (Box-folder 334:3)
      - Annual Reports, 1917, 2 copies (Box-folder 334:3)
      - Annual Reports, 1918, 2 copies (Box-folder 334:3)
      - General Balance Sheets and Analysis, 30 Jun 1912, 1 vol. (Box 334)
      - General Balance Sheets and Analysis, 30 Jun 1913, 1 vol. (Box 334)
      - General Balance Sheets and Analysis, 30 Jun 1914, 1 vol. (Box 335)
      - General Balance Sheets and Analysis, 30 Jun 1915, 1 vol. (Box 335)
      - General Balance Sheets and Analysis, 30 Jun 1916, 1 vol. (Box 335)
      - General Balance Sheets and Analysis, 31 Dec 1916, 1 vol. (Box 335)
      - General Balance Sheets and Analysis, 31 Dec 1917, 1 vol. (Box 335)
      - General Balance Sheets and Analysis, 31 Dec 1918, 1 vol. (Box 335)
      - General Balance Sheets and Analysis, 31 Dec 1919, 1 vol. (Box 335)
      - Betterment, 1893-1909 (Box-folder 336:1)
        Includes analysis of expenditures for equipment, road and property.